Guide to the Rice University Rice Design Alliance Records, 1972-2016 UA 080
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Rice Design Alliance Records
1972-2016
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University. Rice Design Alliance
UA 080
.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The Rice Design Alliance, established in 1973, is a nonprofit educational organization dedicated to increasing greater public awareness of architecture, design and the environment. These materials represent RDA lectures, seminars, symposiums, exhibits and tours, which have involved the general public in issues related to the design of public spaces, parks, office buildings, retail centers and residential neighborhoods.
Organizational History
The Rice Design Alliance, established in 1973, is a nonprofit educational organization dedicated to increasing greater public awareness of architecture, design and the environment. By sponsoring lectures seminars, symposiums, exhibits and tours, RDA involves the general public in issues related to the design of public spaces, parks, office buildings, retail centers and residential neighborhoods. Its biannual journal, Cite: The Architecture and Design Review of Houston, addresses design issues in the greater Houston area. Membership in RDA is open to the general public. Excerpted from "Think Big," the 1990 gala invitation from RDA.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of two 0.25 ft. boxes. It includes the RDA Charter, a history and other related materials, such as membership brochures, grants, news clippings and press releases. These are numerous brochures for tours, exhibits and film presentations and lectures as well as invitations to galas.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Notes
The contents of the collection were previously part of the Woodson Information Files.
Related Material
See also Cite: The Architecture and Design Review of Houston, located in both Brown Fine Arts Library and Woodson Research Center, NA 9127 .H7 C5.
Index Terms
Subjects
Education; Architecture; Universities and colleges
Document Types
lecture notes; clippings (information artifacts); programs (documents); minutes (administrative records)
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University; Rice University. Rice Design Alliance
- Series I: Charter and History, 105399
  - Charter-Certificate of Incorporation, 1972, 105401 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History, n.d., 105400 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Members, Meetings, & Events, 105383
  - Membership, 1973, n.d., 105398 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meetings, 1990, 105397 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter, 1976, 105396 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Grants, 1979, 1991, 1993, 1995, 1997, 1999, 2001, 105395 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - News clippings, general, 1973-75, 1980, 1989, 1990, 1992-98, 2000, 105394 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Competitions, 1992, 1996, 2001, 105393 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Exhibits, 1988-90, 1994, 1997-2001, n.d., 105392 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Film presentations, n.d., 105391 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Galas, 1987-94, 1997, 1999-2000, 105390 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Lectures, general, 1975, 1980, 1992-92, n.d., 105389 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lectures, 1980's, 105388 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Lectures, 1990's, 105387 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Lectures, 2000-, 105386 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Tours/lectures, 1980, 1990-91, 1993-2001, n.d., 105385 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Press Releases, 1973-74, 1976, 105384 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series III: Publications
  - Rice Design Alliance Architectural Tour Brochures (12), 1983-2016 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Event pamphlets, 1996-2012 (Box 2, Folder 2)